Sometimes it scares me to think...
where it's coming from. you know?
Like...
there's someone else
inside there. not me.
Well...
what if I...
what if I lose it and never get it back?
What would I do then?
Take a listen to this again.
I want to...
do something with it.
Um... I've got... I think I've got it.
The music part.
it worked out in my head. but...
I don't know anything else
except that it should...
it should sound like.
you know. a cry. but...
in sort of a good way or something.
I want these voices
at the end just to...
sound...
All right. Chuck. let's have it.
I wish they all could be California...
We don't want to take 16...
Help me. help me. help me...
Baby...
There we go.
I'm losing it.
I'm losing the whole record.
That'd be great.
Something's going to happen.
All right. here we go.
You're grass and I'm a power mower.
If everybody had an ocean...
Across the USA...
Then everybody'd be surfin'...
Like Californi-a...
You see them wearing their baggies...
Huarache sandals. too...
A bushy. bushy blonde hairdo...
Yeah. we all grew up
in Hawthorne. California.
The brothers here.
Dennis. Brian. and Carl.
Carl.
They all live in the same house
and I grew up...
a few blocks down.
Al... Al. where did you live?
Well. it's been building up
inside of me...
for. oh. I don't know how long...
I don't know why. but I keep thinking...
something's bound to go wrong...
- Ooh
- But she looks in my eyes...
and makes me realize...
and she says...
I have watched you...
on the shore...
standing by the ocean's roar...
with a different melody.
It's the same chord progression...
- with a spin-off.
- Mm-hmm.
So. my part in the chorus
against the band...
alternates with the intro
backing the new melody.
Just gets around.
Gets around. Clever.
Round. round. get around.
I get around...
- I get around
- Yeah...
Get around. 'round. 'round. 'round...
- I get around...
- Okay. hold it!
'Round. 'round. 'round. I get around
Get around. 'round. 'round.
I get around...
I'm a real cool head...
- I'm making real good bread
- Get around. 'round. 'round...
Well. you knew all along...
that your dad was
getting wise to you now...
You shouldn't have lied now.
you shouldn't have lied...
And since he took your set of keys...
you've been thinking that
your fun is all through now.
You shouldn't have lied now.
you shouldn't have lied.
But you can come along with me...
'cause we've got
a lot of things to do now.
You shouldn't have lied now.
you shouldn't have lied...
And we'll have fun. fun. fun...
now that Daddy took the T-bird away.
Fun. fun. fun now that Daddy
took the T-bird away...
Excuse me.
What?
Oh.
Hi. how are you?
I'm fine. thanks. Are these your shoes?
What? Yeah. yeah. they're my shoes.
I didn't want to. you know.
mess up the car...
because I jog.
See. I jog on the beach and. um...
I get sand in my shoes. you know?
So...
Well. that's very considerate.
But I... you know.
I also get sand in my socks.
I got holes in my socks.
so I did make a mess anyways.
So. I'm sorry about that.
What are you going to do?
You're going to get sand in the car.
It's no problem.
Can I help you today?
I'd like to buy a car.
Cadillac. you know?
Great.
- You've come to the right place.
- Yeah.
This is the Fleetwood.
- Wow.
- My personal favorite.
What do you think?
I don't know.
Well. take your time.
there's no pressure.
Blue is a very calm color.
Is this guy a friend of yours?
I feel like he's watching us.
No. he's not my friend.
He's my bodyguard.
Come on.
Something like that.
It's a funny word. isn't it. bodyguard?
- Uh...
- Bodyguard.
- Are we on "Candid Camera"?
- No.
No. no. no. I do need a car.
Can we just sit in here for a minute?
Sure.
Well. the master lock feature works.
We know that much.
Hmm.
My brother died.
Oh. Oh. I'm...
I'm so sorry.
He drowned.
A few years ago.
Two.
But I'm all...
broken up about it still. you know?
I mean. he wasn't even 40 yet.
That is... that's terrible.
- So sad.
- Yeah.
But I just don't get it.
I think about it every day.
and I just don't get it.
I guess it's better just
not to think about it. right?
Just...
force it out of your mind.
Sure. Yeah. I can understand that.
I'm not married anymore.
Okay.
Do you have a pen I could use?
I guess I need
a little piece of paper. too.
Uh. sure. Just. um...
Thank you.
Brian. come on out of the car.
- I'm Brian.
- Melinda.
- Hi.
- Come on. Brian.
- I want this car.
-
- The Fleetwood?
No. no. yeah. but I want this car. Okay?
I want this car.
This one we're sitting in.
- Oh. the floor model?
- Yes. it's your favorite. right?
- You want...
- It's special. You understand?
- Can I have it?
- Sure.
- Okay.
- Yes.
- Hey.
- What's happening. guys?
- Hi. Gene.
- Hi. I'm Dr. Eugene Landy.
- Hi.
How are you?
I'm Brian's brother from another mother.
- What's up?
- I want the blue Fleetwood. Gene.
- Really?
- Yeah.
You sure you don't want a Maserati?
- No offense.
- None taken.
- No. that one.
- Really?
- It's her favorite.
- Okay.
Well. I'm going to expect
a deal here. You know?
Something worth our while.
Do you know who this man is?
Brian Wilson.
Brian Wilson of the Beach Boys.
- You didn't mention that.
- Well. 'cause that stuff doesn't matter.
That's ego stuff. You know?
Are you kidding me?
I love your music. I grew up on it.
So. thank you.
That makes me feel really good.
Melinda Ledbetter.
Okay.
- Melinda Ledbetter.
- Right? It's a nice name.
Uh. why don't you get started
on the paperwork?
- Okay?
- Will do.
Great. And thank you again
for your help.
Let's go. Brian.
Come on. guy.
I think it's a good choice.
- You feel good about it?
- Yeah.
- You sure?
Okay.
What the hell was that about?
I'm not really sure.
You okay?
Yeah.
Ladies and gentlemen.
we're about to start our descent.
Please return your seats
to an upright position...
and fasten your seat belts.
You okay?
I think I'm having a heart attack.
Brian! Brian!
- Brian! Brian! Brian!
- Get him something!
- Bring us a pillow!
- Breathe!
- Give me the pillow!
- Where's the pillow?!
Give me the pillow!
- Brian! Brian!
- Breathe!
Are you choking? Are you choking?
- I don't want to die!
- Hey!
- Hey. hey. hey. hey.
- I don't want to die!
Brian. look at me.
Look at me! Look at me!
Look at me! Look at me. Look at me.
It's okay.
Hi.
You good?
Nowhere to run to. baby.
It was weird.
It was like I was in a movie
or something.
There was music. like always...
but then it got dark and scary.
I couldn't breathe.
Like someone was holding
his hand over my mouth.
Hey. Brian. You doing okay. baby?
Yeah. I'm good. Mare.
Okay. just checking.
Yeah. then I started hearing things.
Strange things.
- People talking.
- What. like voices?
Like. uh...
like voices in your head?
No!
Well. kind of. Yeah.
Maybe I'm cuckoo for Cocoa Puffs!
Cuckoo for Cocoa Puffs!
It was kind of scary.
I think it's just Dad. You know?
Messing with your head.
We're too big for him
to take the belt to us anymore...
so he's got to use
his black magic shit or something.
Ah. come on. It's not Dad.
- Yeah...
- Something's off.
It's being on the road.
You know. being up there. It's freaky.
I get nervous onstage. too. Bri.
- I mean. we all probably do.
- No. but this is different.
Anyway. you don't need me
standing up there...
looking like a jerk.
I'll be better back here at home.
Making music.
I just want to be home.
I got all kinds of new ideas...
new sounds...
new harmonies...
new instruments.
You hear the new Beatles?
- Yeah.
- The "Rubber Soul"? Yeah.
I heard it was about
John Lennon having an affair.
It's amazing!
I mean. it works like a whole.
It's like a whole album.
Everything fits together. no fat.
Like an album of folk songs.
but the sounds are really far out.
- Lots of overdubbing.
- They stole our backing vocal.
You know. we go.
La. la. la. la. la. la...
And then they changed it to...
De. de. de. de. de. de. de. de. de...
I thought it said.
"Tit. tit. tit. tits. titties."
- No?
- Denny.
We can't let them get ahead of us!
J...
I can take us further.
If you let me
stay at home in the studio.
It's what I need to do.
And I promise. when you come back...
I will have stuff for you
that will blow your minds.
Bri!
Fine. but you just keep
your head on straight.
- Okay. Bri?
- I will!
- Hey. Brian!
- I will.
Straight as a die.
Hey. straight as a what?
What does that even mean?
You're going to die in a straight line?
I have no idea. I heard Dad use it once.
Oh. never use it again.
It's going to be strange
to be in Japan without you. brother.
Yeah. who's going to fold
our clothes now?
Bri!
Carl. Dennis. come on.
guys. come sit with us.
Okay. I'll be right over.
Everybody in!
One of these days.
you are going to break...
your skull open
if you're not careful. Bri.
I'm going to make the greatest album
ever made. Mare!
I know you are. baby.
I know you are.
Ben. two more minutes. I'm almost ready.
You can lock up.
- This is Melinda.
- Friday night.
- 6:00?
- Hello?
- What? Wrong ear.
- Put it on the other ear.
- Hello? Uh. hi.
- Jesus.
Is this Mel... Melinda?
Yes. this is Melinda.
Melinda Ledbetter?
Yes.
Hi.
It's Brian Wilson from the Beach Boys.
Hi. Brian Wilson from the Beach Boys.
Melinda!
Melinda Ledbetter!
Are you there?!
Hi.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- I'm great!
- You look really great.
- Thank you.
- You want to go?
- Oh. did you... yeah.
I...
- I forgot your apartment number.
- Ah. Well...
It's a good thing
the loudspeaker worked.
Yeah.
Why does it feel like
the prom all of a sudden?
I'm not sure.
Thank you.
- Hey. Melinda.
- Hi.
- You look great.
- Uh. hi!
Gazing at people...
- This song is so great.
- Some hand in hand...
I love it.
Such a beautiful song.
- What's that?
- Excuse me?
I couldn't hear what you said.
What'd you say to Brian?
Uh. I... I just said
that this song is...
is so great. I love it.
- Why? Why?
- No. it's a great song.
It's fantastic. You're right. Timeless.
Thoughts they cannot defend...
Just what you want to be...
Well...
I guess this is good night.
Good night.
- Okay.
- Would you like me to call you again?
Would you like to call me again?
Or... are you just asking
'cause you were told to?
Both things.
- Both.
- I really appreciate your honesty.
I really do. I don't meet
a lot of honest people anymore.
I'll tell you what.
I'm going to be home
most of the day Sunday.
Give me a call if you feel like it.
If you don't. that's fine. too.
There's no pressure.
I'm going to call you.
- Cool.
Good night.
I may not always love you...
but long as there are stars above you...
you never need to doubt it.
I'll make you so sure about it.
And God only knows...
what I'd be without you.
If you should ever leave me...
well. life would still go on.
believe me.
The world could show nothing to me...
so what good would living do me?...
And God only knows...
what I'd be without you.
And the last verse
repeats one more time...
and the chorus will harmonize
over and over at the end.
It's still rough. I know.
but it's getting there.
It's right for Carl's voice.
You like it. Dad?
I mean. it'll get better.
The vocals will...
counterpoint the backing track.
Real soulful.
Oh. you don't want
my advice or my meddling.
Well. just tell me what you think.
Not much use for me. is there?
With your mom living on her own.
Come on. we're still a family.
Families don't fire their own father.
I don't want to start
that argument again.
- I'm not arguing.
- If I say something now. you'll argue.
Then don't say anything.
Forget it!
Forget what? Forget what?
- You don't like the song.
- I never said that.
I can tell.
Just say something!
I would change the title.
The Capris had a tune out
called "God Only Knows"...
- in '55. '54.
- Never mind that.
Did you close your eyes
like I asked you to?
Tony and I think...
if you close your eyes.
you can see a place...
where something is happening.
It's like being blind. but because
you're blind. you can see more.
Don't you think
it's a spiritual kind of thing?
I don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
I closed my eyes. didn't see a thing.
I don't know.
maybe it could be something...
with the right arrangement.
Well. yeah. I have French horns on it...
and flutes. tambourines.
sleigh bells. piano. bass...
real complex key shifts.
Frankly. if you really want to know...
I don't care for it.
It's too wishy-washy.
If you leave me. why leave me?
Life will go on. why go on living?
It's not like a Beach Boys song.
Your brothers are going to hate it.
- It's a love song.
- It's a suicide note.
Didn't you just say it could be something
with the right arrangement?!
Well. I gave it another thought. okay?
And if you can't keep
your voice down in my house...
get out!
Hey. Carol.
- How's it going?
- Good. Good to see you.
Groovy shades.
Lyle. how's it going?
- Hal. hey. Good to see you.
- Hey. You. too.
I want you to meet Tony Asher.
Tony Asher. this is Hal Blaine.
The greatest drummer working today.
And you never heard of him. have you?
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
That's the secret.
All these guys. Hal. Tommy. Carol. Earl...
the whole band.
I mean. they're probably...
the best in the business.
but they're studio musicians...
so nobody's ever heard of them.
It's crazy!
- Huh?
- Yeah. oh. yeah.
Yeah. Here you go.
Kettle drums?
Thought we were doing rock 'n' roll.
Ah. a whole new bag.
So what do we got going here. Brian?
Uh. I don't know. Hal. Just some ideas.
Try something.
Oh. excuse me.
- Bum. bum. bum.
- Yup.
Yeah. let's try it.
Mmm.
That's exactly how I want it.
You know what I'm going to do?
Let's add a little tie right here.
I think this will sound better...
- a little smoother right there.
- You want to tie the first one?
Okay. this is "I'm Waiting
For the Day." take six.
Here we go. One. two. one. two. three.
Oh. hey! That was out of sight.
I mean. it really was. Al.
How did you play that?
- I don't know.
- What?
The. uh...
How did you play that?
- It was a mistake.
- Well. if you repeat a mistake...
every four bars.
it's not a mistake anymore.
- See what I mean?
- I love it.
All right.
That was great. Okay. let's do it again.
Remember. it's the higher octave
on the upbeats and the bridge.
Hey. Brian?
- Yeah. I love that.
- Brian?
- Yeah?
- I think you might've screwed up here.
Really? Let me see.
Well. you've got Lyle playing in D...
- and the rest of us are in A major.
- Yeah. that's right.
How does that work?
Two bass lines in two different keys?
Well. it works in my head.
It's all playing in my head.
The orchestration
and the five vocal parts.
I think it's going to work.
Let's try it.
Oh. Hal? Hal?
Here's how I want you
to do it. It goes. uh...
Two. three. four.
So it's. uh...
the first beat
on the last bar of the intro.
Boom! Two. three. four.
There's the North Star right there.
- That's the North Star?
- Yeah. yeah. You knew that.
- I really didn't.
- Come on.
- I mean. it's a bright star.
- Have you ever...
have you ever seen this before?
- Never like this.
- Yeah.
I used to love
coming here as a kid. you know?
I love the feel of this place.
I really wanted to take you here.
- You did?
- Yeah.
Demonstration booths.
Do you remember those?
- In the department store?
- Yeah. and that's when I first heard...
The Four Freshmen...
and immediately my mind just...
I mean. it's... like magic.
Something happened and...
so I listened to those harmonies
and study them after school.
and I would teach them to my brothers.
And we'd all sing.
And then I would teach them
to my parents...
and we'd all be sitting around singing.
My brothers and my parents
and everybody.
Everybody.
Wow. That sounds like
such a wonderful childhood.
Yeah. it was really nice...
except for when my dad
was beating on us...
all the time. you know? Like...
He was a really hard. hard guy.
You know. like. um...
There's a spanking. You know that sound?
You know a certain kind of spanking...
and it sounds like a...
you know. like...
But the way we had it. you know?
When it came out of him. it's...
You know?
Really hard.
Come on. let's give
these guys some privacy.
- You know. we laugh about it.
- Babe. I can't just...
- Doug. come on.
- You know. back in those days?
We laugh about all that. but...
it was pretty tough business.
Pretty tough business.
Hey.
- I'm so sorry.
- No. what? About what?
They're okay.
They come here all the time.
- It's their favorite spot.
- No. Brian. about your dad.
Oh. yeah.
You know. spare... spare the rod...
spoil the child.
You know I'm 96% deaf...
in my right ear because
my dad whacked me all the time?
He was a really hard man...
and he was a not very happy man...
but. uh...
in some ways I love my dad.
you know. because...
he scared me and he scared me so much...
I think he actually scared me
into making good records.
You know? I mean. he had this. like...
competitive spirit
that really blew my mind and...
What about your mom?
She stayed out of all of it. mostly.
I think she drank a lot. You know?
That's how she...
she... she dealt with it.
I haven't seen her in... three years?
- What?
- Gene doesn't think it's a good idea...
for me to be in touch
with my family right now.
I haven't seen my daughters in...
two years.
You have two daughters.
Yeah. Yeah.
I wasn't a very good father
to them. you know?
Because I was drinking and drugging
when I should have been...
you know. a parent.
And. uh...
you know. I made a mess of my life...
lost control of my life.
It's a weird trip...
but...
anyway. they live in Encino
with their mom.
Well. shit.
Yeah.
But it's not so bad now anymore.
You know?
- Good.
- Uh-huh.
Good.
Look. listen to me.
I'm just going on and on.
- It's my boring life...
- It's not boring.
It is. but what about you. Melinda?
I mean. my God. you're so...
You're such good fun
and you're... you're so...
so tender and so sweet.
I mean...
why don't you have a... boyfriend?
Oh. well...
There was someone.
He was no good. He broke my heart.
He shouldn't have done that.
Well. I shouldn't have let him.
Aww. sh...
Fuck. Tony. you holding those keys down?
- Yeah. yeah.
- Okay.
Can I have another
bobby pin. please. Hal?
Okay. keep the keys down. Tony.
Here we go.
Yeah. so. uh. right here.
No. give it. uh...
like...
There's like a gasp in between.
Cut! I think we got it.
Chuck. mix that in. uh.
with the sound of the train...
going by at the end of "Caroline. No."
- You got it. Brian.
- Hey. Chuck...
you think we could get a horse in here?
Hey. kid.
Brian.
Brian!
Brian! You got a light?
I spilled coffee on my matches in there.
Tough day at the office?
Well...
my family is coming in tomorrow...
the band. they're...
Well. sometimes they're tough. you know?
Let me tell you something.
We're all pros. you know?
We've played with everyone.
Heard it all.
You name them. we've played with them.
Sinatra. Dean Martin...
Elvis. Phil Spector...
Sam Cooke. everyone!
And we all studied in goddamn
conservatories. for Christ's sake.
But...
but you...
you got to know...
that you're touched. kid.
You've blown our minds.
- More than Phil Spector?
- Ah. Phil's got nothing on you.
Oh. man.
No. the band is going to love it.
Every note of it.
You're a talented young man.
Hang in there. man. I'll see ya.
- I'll see ya tomorrow. Hal.
- Wow. nice place.
- Yeah. come on in.
Let me show you around.
- Oh. wow.
- This is my room.
This is my room.
- Oh. nice!
- Yeah. I got to pick it.
What do you mean?
Well. you know. I got another house
a little bit up the coast. you know?
- You do?
- But Gene wants me to live. you know...
in a more controlled environment.
So he's living in that one
and I'm living here.
You know. not so many
distractions and memories.
But I got to pick the room.
- Wow.
- Ch... ch... check this out.
Look at this.
That's absolutely beautiful.
Thanks.
What is it?
Oh. that's just something that I...
came up with when I saw you.
What are you going to do with it?
Nothing. it's gone.
That was just for you.
That's so incredible. Oh. my God...
that just. like. came out of you.
Is that how it works? Or just...
Yeah. Sometimes.
Sometimes your inner voice
wants to express itself...
and every once in a while.
every blue moon...
your soul... comes out to play.
- You know?
- Wow.
Can't be rushed.
It's like a kid. it's just nature...
but... yeah.
Can I ask you something personal?
- Personal?
- Kind of.
Sure. I'm an open book.
Did you really spend two years in bed?
No...
more like three.
At least. that's what I tell people.
I got out at night
sometimes in my bathrobe.
Do you like matzo ball soup?
I don't know. I don't think...
- I've ever had matzo ball soup.
- No?
It's really good.
My ex-wife was Jewish.
did I tell you that?
- No.
- That's when I first had it.
- Oh.
- At Marilyn's parents' house.
They're really nice parents.
She saved my life.
Marilyn?
Mare.
I wasn't a very good husband.
I told you...
but...
we were only kids when we got married.
- She was 16. 16.
- That's crazy.
I think it's
an acquired taste. you know?
- Marriage?
- Matzo ball soup.
We should go one day. you know?
- Go to Canter's and try it.
- Sure.
- Do you want to try it?
- Yeah. I would. Why not?
- I don't want to force you to.
- You wouldn't be.
- It's not going to kill you or anything.
- I would hope not.
You know. I mean.
just have a little bit.
- It's good to try new things in life.
- Okay. I will.
I will try to keep an open mind.
- It's important to try things.
- Good.
- New things.
I agree.
Brian...
time for your pills.
Come on.
- One minute.
- Oh.
Melinda...
you ever hear of the. um...
"Underground Dictionary"?
Thank you. sweetheart.
- Uh. no.
- Well. I published it.
- 1971.
- Huh.
It's an amazing book. It's a. uh...
lexicon for subcultural speak.
It's a reference book
for professionals...
of all kinds to learn how to talk to...
the subcultures of the time.
- Bikers. hookers. surfers...
- Hey.
- Are you okay?
- ...junkies. blacks...
- Yeah.
- What does he have you on?
I get allergies.
I get allergies. so. um...
I get a little drowsy.
They're the toughest ones to talk to.
Right. Brian?
I'm... I'm... I'm hungry. Gene.
- ...It was a real bitchin' concept book.
- Gene. I'm hungry.
Kind of ahead of its time
and it got a lot of attention.
- Frankly.
- Gene. I'm hungry.
It's coming.
Uh. far out. right on. out of sight...
uh. smokey tits. bonnaroo.
Uh. super wicked. wiggy.
How about that? All right.
We got one ready here.
Guest of honor first.
- Oh.
- There you go. ma'am.
- Nope.
- You know. I'm...
- You... you should have it.
- No. no. He's not as hungry...
- as he thinks he is.
- I'm... I'm hungry.
No. you're not. You know what?
You need to drink more water
and you would be full.
- I think he's hungry.
- Go ahead. No. patience is a virtue.
- Seriously. he can wait.
- I think he should...
- I can share.
- Taste it.
Good? Far out.
Far out.
- Hey. Gene.
- Yeah?
Exactly what allergies
does he suffer from anyway?
Don't you worry about that.
Brian's medications
are very carefully administered...
if you must know.
You know what?
No. God damn it! Jesus Christ!
Seriously?! Seriously?!
You have got to learn
to wait your goddamn turn!
Jesus Christ!
Now this is what happens. okay?
- I'm hungry.
- No!
You are not goddamn hungry!
You think you're hungry!
Do you you understand
the goddamn difference?!
Wait your turn!
You have got to be kidding me!
You have no idea
the consequences from this.
- Okay?
- No.
No idea. man! Come on!
Jesus Christ! Rob?
First of all. I want to apologize
about the other night.
I can get worked up
sometimes when it comes to Brian.
Now. I should have
met with you earlier...
but with all of that said...
I really don't want you to be alarmed...
by what. uh. I'm going
to talk to you about now.
But you should know
that you are dealing with...
a very. very... sick man.
There's no other way to say it. Sorry.
Well. how sick is he?
Brian is a... paranoid schizophrenic.
But you really
do not need to be alarmed...
because I have it under control.
I am the control... so to speak.
When I started working with Brian...
he weighed. what... 300 pounds?
He spent all day in bed...
eating bloody steaks
and a lot of junk food.
- Self-medicating.
- Oh.
Drinking. among other things.
Uh. just not dealing.
not able to look me in the eye.
Not able to look anybody in the eye.
Frankly. suicidal.
- So...
- Really?
I pulled him out of the grave...
and I stood him up...
and I taught him
how to start living again.
He was very open.
I mean. he... I... thought.
You know. he told me...
he was taking medication for anxiety...
- and a little depression.
- First thing. don't...
believe everything that Brian tells you.
He's. uh...- he's a little boy
in a man's body.
I mean. there's a lot
of playacting going on...
in Brian World.
Are you in love with him?
Please understand something.
I hope you do.
It's my job... it's my duty...
to approve anyone that
Brian is spending time with.
And I mean everyone.
Yeah? So...
If you want to continue to see him...
well. then there's
going to have to be some rules.
Um. for example...
if Brian calls you.
asks you out for a date...
well. that's fantastic...
but I need you to call me
directly... immediately.
And afterwards. I think it would be...
therapeutically useful...
if you report to me
everything that happened.
Your thoughts. your feelings.
Uh. his thoughts. his feelings.
And so far as you can report
on those things objectively...
from your perspective. You follow me?
I'm giving you
unprecedented access here.
But... I need you...
to work with me.
All right. you want a cup of tea?
But. you know. your suspicion...
is just like Brian's initial paranoia.
His desire not to get better.
But. you know. that came from...
no sense of self-worth...
no belief in himself.
no ability to trust.
You have the ability to trust. Melinda?
Come on.
I'm helping a great man
learn how to be alive again.
Why not trust me?
I'm going to try. Gene.
I just don't know you.
But I know you.
As I told you. it is my job.
Okay?
You think of yourself
as an independent woman. right?
Hagerty girl. right?
Successful modeling career...
some long-term relationships...
disappointments.
Your last boyfriend
took you for a bit of a ride.
Had a girl in every port.
And now you...
sell cars.
Well. we all do what we can.
We do.
And life can be painful.
I know. That's all I'm saying.
You know. I don't believe
in coincidences.
There's a reason we met.
All of us. Let's work together.
Help me out and let me help you...
and help me help Brian. Okay?
Thanks. Gene. Thank you.
Take good care of yourself.
Konnichiwa.
- Where's my favorite big brother?
- Denny!
How you doing? Oh. hey.
Hey. man. forget about California girls.
- Tokyo is where it's at!
- Tokyo girls? Denny.
- I missed you. Bri.
- Oh. it's good to see you.
Hey. look. I got you a souvenir.
Hey. it matches your shirt. It's cool.
- Hey. Al. good to see you!
- Good to see you.
- Bruce. thanks for being there for me.
- It's an honor. Brian.
No way to fill your shoes.
but I did my best.
- Cousin.
- Mike!
- Good to see you.
- Good to see you!
- What happened? Look at that beard!
- I know. I know...
but what happened to you?
You're getting a little tubby here.
What happened?
You should go on a fast with me.
Well. I'm already eating
as fast as I can.
Well. fatty. we are ready
to rock to your roll. man.
- Let's... let's listen to some tracks.
- Good to see you.
- All right!
- What you got cooking?
You know. Carl. a samurai sword
would have been...
Well. yeah. but I just...
- it was in the airport.
- Does it look cool?
I try hard to be strong...
but sometimes I fail myself...
And after all I've promised you...
so faithfully...
you still...
believe...
in me.
I want to cry...
Hey. Brian? This chorus.
The lyrics.
Don't you think it's a little. uh...
What?
"Hang on to your ego."
what are you trying to say?
Uh...
well...
- "hang on to your ego."
- Yeah. ego.
Are you saying...
Is this a druggie song?
Is this a drug song?
- A drug song?
- Yes. "hang on to your ego."
Uh. "Hang on. but I know
that you're going to lose the fight."
I don't know. I... I don't think
it's a drug song...
- whatever that is.
- "They come on like they're peaceful...
but inside they're so uptight.
They trip through the day
and waste all their thoughts at night."
Sounds like a druggie to me. Brian.
- Druggie?!
- Don't pretend like you don't know...
- what I'm talking about here!
- Okay. it's about ego. That's all.
It's about ego?
That's all? Okay.
I'm not trying to be
a tough guy here. okay?
I'm just asking a question.
I just want to know if it's a drug song.
If it's not a drug song.
I want to know what it's about.
Does it sound like
a drug song to anybody else?
Okay. it's not a drug song.
but is it about...
I don't know. it sounds fine.
Okay. okay. so hang on...
we'll hang on to our ego.
Let's all just hang on to our egos
and record the song.
She made me feel so bad.
She made my heart feel sad.
She made my days go wrong.
And then my nights so long.
You've got to keep in mind...
love is here...
today. and it's gone...
tomorrow. It's here and gone so fast.
You have that attached to the flash?
Brian. your voice is on the track.
Stop. please.
Yeah!
No.
- Yes.
- What do you mean. "yeah"?
I mean. yeah. I left them in.
I like it.
- We're listening here.
- You left them in?
The voices? The talking in your head?
That's part of the song?
- It's part of the music.
- Keep in mind love is here.
It's just like all
the other instruments we use.
- Play the studio.
- Today. and it's gone...
- Play the studio?
- ...tomorrow. it's here...
- I like it. Bri.
They're not going to hear it anyways.
It's buried under there.
I... I think it's really cool.
- Can we stop it. please?
- Jesus. come on. Mike.
No. no. no. it's amateurish.
It's amateurish.
It's hip. man! It's fun!
It's now!
That's where things are happening.
- Brian. it's not.
- Now!
No. this is not fun.
- Not the music. not the lyrics.
- I think it's fun.
Now. it's not all bad.
don't get me wrong...
but it's not Beach Boys fun.
- We've done Beach Boys fun.
- And we had hits. we had lots of hits!
- Why are we arguing right now. Mike?
- There's not one hit...
on this album. guys!
I don't care how many car horns
and bicycle bells...
and jingle-jangle
or whatever you put in there.
They're not going to buy
something depressing like that!
- Depressing?
- Even the happy songs are sad.
We need to write
some of the old stuff again. fellas.
- That's all I'm saying.
- The old stuff is old!
- So we'll make it new again!
- I can't go back in time!
We're not surfers. we never have been...
and real surfers
don't dig our music anyway.
- They don't.
- Okay. I can't write about the summer...
and fun and summer
and summer and fun and cars!
I got different stuff inside me.
I got to get it out.
Oh. jeez. would you listen to yourself?
You've "got to get it out"?
- Who are you? Mozart?!
- Everyone shut up!
Carl. play it again.
It's a new creative bag.
- We've got to keep growing!
- Oh. jeez.
None of these guys have played
one single note on the entire album.
It's like you're making
your own record with our voices. Brian.
Dennis played.
- A little bit. Carl. too.
- "A little bit."
For crying out loud.
would you listen to yourself?
First you wanted
to stop touring with us...
and we accepted that. that's fine.
Bruce is doing great.
But now it's like we're barely a part...
of the Brian Wilson Band!
You can't just do
whatever the hell you want. Brian!
The other guys might not say this...
but you are letting us down.
If you stop thinking about
yourself for two seconds...
you might realize that.
Break my heart.
I want to go and cry.
It's so sad...
to watch a sweet thing die.
Oh. Caroline. why?
Could I ever find in you again...
the things that made me
love you so much then?
Could we ever bring them back...
once they have gone?
Oh. Caroline. no.
Sorry. sorry. Brian.
but apparently your dad...
just drove up.
I thought you'd want to know.
- Shit!
- Hide the pot!
Fuck!
- Uncle Murray!
- Boys?
- Hey. hey. hey.
- Mike. Al.
Good to see you. boys.
Dad. good to see you. sir.
Where's Brian?
There you are. How you doing?
Good. good.
Listen to this.
Chuck. if you would be so kind.
My new band.
This is where you guys
need to get back to.
This is a hit.
Check out the harmonies.
- I live...
- And the arrangement?
- for the sun...
- Doesn't this guy sound just like Brian?
I'm telling you.
I am taking these guys...
all the way to the top!
That's great. Dad.
You're doing your own thing.
- Such a lucky...
- Chuck. let me know when we're ready...
- for the next take.
- Sure. Brian.
Brian. come back here.
Listen to what a gold record sounds like.
Sun. sun. sun...
Doesn't this guy sound just like Brian?
I don't give a shit. Brian!
I don't give a shit!
I just want to say. man.
Listen man. you're the artist.
Right? You want God.
You should have God.
Don't you want to be out there
rocking the boat?
What is this? 1939? Mike says?
Who cares what Mike says?
Sing what's in your soul. man.
Let the world stand on its head.
Don't listen to
the record company suits.
Don't listen to anybody.
Listen to you.
You're the genius.
We're the band as far as anybody
in the know is concerned.
- Right?!
- Sorry. man. It's true.
Listen. Brian.
I got something for you. man.
Something for you. man.
It'll take all that crap
out of your head. man.
Where were you?
I did LSD.
Really?
What was it like?
Well...
at first it was nothing...
then everything.
And then I did it again.
Again?
Oh. I heard the most...
a whole other kind of music.
I saw things...
that you can't see.
Like what?
What things that you can't see?
Like...
weird things?
Things like God.
- What?
- I saw God and...
he showed me everything.
Oh. he showed me the future. Mare.
Oh. I'm so sorry.
Brian?
- I'm so sorry.
- Brian. what are you talking about?
Bri?
What is the matter? Hey...
Hey. hey. hey. hey. hey. hey. hey. hey.
No. hey. hey...
It's okay. It's okay. Bri.
Here. come here. Come here.
- Look at me. Come on. Brian.
- My grandfather and me...
- Look at me.
- ...around Nassau town...
we did roam...
drinking all night.
Got into a fight.
Well. I feel so broke up...
I want to go home.
So hoist up the John B's sail.
See how the mainsail sets.
Call for the captain ashore.
Let me go home.
I want to go home.
Yeah. yeah.
Well. I feel so broke up...
I want to go home.
The first mate. he got drunk.
Broke in the captain's trunk.
The constable had to come...
and take him away.
Sheriff John Stone...
Why don't you leave me alone?
Hey. Evan!
- Evan. could you turn that off?
- I feel so broken up.
What? It's a tribute to you. Brian!
We're stoked to have you. man.
Okay. Could you turn it off anyway...
because it sort of destroys my brain.
It does.
I can only imagine.
- Are you having fun?
- I'm having so much fun.
I love being with you.
And not with Gene
and the whole gang watching us.
Oh. uh. Gene told me to tell you...
that he was sorry
about the other day with the barbecue.
That Doug gave me
the wrong dosage and. um...
so that's why he lost his temper...
and that... he's really sorry...
but he wanted us to have a good time.
And that's why it was good
that Evan was here.
- So. you know?
- Yeah. how do you know Evan?
Evan is Gene's son.
Ah. so we're still being watched.
Yeah.
But we can do whatever we want.
I think we should do
whatever we want. too.
What do you want to do?
Evan. will you take that...
- Can you swim?
- Yes.
Evan. will you take the boat in
really close to shore?
I want to show Melinda my house.
Go in past the kelp.
Sure thing!
Whatever makes you happy. Brian.
All right. on the count of three.
I want you to get up...
I want you to jump in the water
and I want you to come over to my house.
- Right now. You ready? Come on.
- What?! Are you serious?
Yeah. let's do it.
Let's ditch this scene
and make out like teenagers.
In or out? Come on.
- In.
- One. two. three!
That is not cool. Brian!
My dad is going to go nuts on me!
Whoo!
Cold? You cold?
I'm exhausted. That was crazy!
Come on. come on. come on.
- You want to hear something funny?
- Of course.
Gene's got me on this thing...
I have to say to myself
five times a day...
"I love you."
It's called self-nourishment.
Can you believe that?
- Does it work?
- I don't know.
Sometimes I wish I had
somebody else to say it to.
Coming!
- Honey...
- Doorbell. Somebody's here.
I didn't hear anything.
You got to hide
under the stairs. you know?
- What?
- Hide under the stairs.
Hide under the stairs.
Brian.
- You got to go. You got to go.
- What?
- You got to go now.
- What's happening?
We overslept.
they're going to come back...
- any minute. You got to go.
- Okay. shh.
You got to go. You got to go now.
- You have to go.
- Did I do something wrong?
No. but they're coming back.
Do you understand?
And when they come back.
it's not going to be a good scene.
- Okay. listen.
- It's not going to be a good scene.
- Hey.
- What?
You're a grown man...
and if you want me to stay.
you can just tell him.
- No. I can't. I can't do that.
- Yes. This is your house.
- No. no. no.
- Do you want me to stay?
He's my legal guardian.
Do you understand?
He can do things to me. All right?
- I don't have a choice.
- You know what? Stop.
- Please. Melinda. go.
- You can stand up to him.
You... listen. you have...
you have friends and family
and daughters...
that you're not allowed to see...
and it's not normal
and you deserve normal.
- Stop.
- He could... he could send me away...
- and throw away the key.
- He's manipulating you.
- No. he isn't.
- Yes.
He's protecting me. He's protecting me.
No. you're protecting him.
Listen. he is taking advantage of you.
He's overmedicating you.
I'm really... I think...
I think that you know it. too.
Please leave. Please. I'm begging you.
Leave. leave.
Just leave. please.
- Okay.
- Don't leave me.
- just go now.
- Do you want me to go or not?
I want you to leave right now.
I don't want you to leave me.
- Okay. I'm not going to leave you.
- Okay? Please.
- Please. please.
- But I'm going. Calm down.
- Please.
- Calm down. I'm going.
Last thing I want to say right now is...
I told you so.
so I'm not going to say it.
That's a whole lot of words
for something you're not saying.
"Pet Sounds" didn't sell.
There. I said it. It flopped.
- But critics loved it.
- The critics don't buy albums.
Well. Mike...
the British buy albums. you know?
- And they went crazy for it.
- It's not even going to go gold.
When's the last time
that happened to us?
Look. you know what I say?
Good. Good. We got it behind us now.
We can get back to our music.
The proof is in the formula.
Like Coca-Cola?
And geometry?
Penicillin and chicks.
Earth to Brian.
- Cocaine is...
- Brian.
You know. Paul McCartney
said that "God Only Knows"...
is the greatest song
ever written. like...
That's because it was a formula.
I will never tie you down.
Left alone with just a memory...
life seems dead and so unreal...
All that's left is loneliness.
There's nothing left to feel.
You don't have to say you love me...
just be close at hand.
Cuz...
Listen. about...
I have this song playing
over and over in my head.
I just don't have
the words or the melody.
Do you have anything?
That's good.
Well. piss on you. Banana.
I like it.
You know. Mom told me once
when we were kids that...
dogs can pick up on vibes
from people like...
like they know when we're happy...
or sad or scared.
Yeah. well...
it's too bad we're not dogs. Right?
Play that for me again.
There's something there.
Really.
Close my eyes.
She's somehow closer now.
Softly smile. I know she must be kind.
It's weird...
how she comes in so strong.
And I wonder
what she's picking up from me.
- I hope it's...
- I'm picking up good vibrations...
She's giving me excitations...
I'm picking up good vibrations...
- Good vibrations
- She's giving me excitations...
Good. good. good. good vibrations...
She's giving me excitations.
Good! Good. we got that part.
Cut it. I want to move to Goldstar
for the next part.
Oh. not again.
Okay. let's cut. please. Okay.
So try to. um...
more staccato. okay?
You guys are the rhythm now.
Um. so. it's like an engine
underneath the song...
Dennis. can you be quiet. please.
while we find the sound? Thanks.
Okay. let's try it again.
More broken up.
One. two. three. four.
Okay. Scott. that sounds great.
Let's see if we can. uh...
take it even further now.
So. like you're not
even playing the cello.
Just. uh. like a propeller.
One. two. three. four.
Yes! Beautiful! I love it!
Okay. stop. One more time.
Okay. and when we modulate there...
it's like shifting gears.
so take... give me...
Just remember to keep laying
into that change.
Okay? One. two. three. four.
Got to keep those...
loving good vibrations...
a-happening with her.
Got to keep those...
loving good vibrations...
a-happening with her.
Got to keep those...
loving good vibrations
a-happening with her.
Okay. Chuck. let's cut
for a second. please.
Okay. let's go again. please.
Let's think of this feel
a little harder. Okay?
A little stronger.
Let's really hit it now. okay?
Here we go!
Okay. one more time. please.
They know the...
They're doing it! Brian.
They've been doing it
for the past three hours!
- Okay. Mike...
- Oh. my God!
you can leave if you
don't want to be here.
Thank you. I'm working
with the cello players.
Okay. let's try it again. please.
One more time.
Take 32. here we go.
Um. I would like to make a toast...
um. to "Good Vibrations."...
Brian's pocket symphony to God.
And the best-selling single
the Beach Boys ever had...
ever.
Brian. the suits
at Capitol must be happy.
Yeah. I guess you can tell the record
company to go screw themselves.
I mean. you can do
whatever you want. Brian.
Right?
Now what are you going to do
with all that freedom?
- Did my dad call?
- No.
He hasn't. Do you want me to get him?
Hey. Van. what do you and Brian
have cooking?
You know. just your basic...
American songbook. neoclassical ditties.
Basic Copland.
Gershwin. Hank Williams...
a little bit of Irving Berlin
and Kurt Weill.
Just a sprinkle of Beethoven
and the Beach Boys.
So nothing too ambitious.
Brian wants to call it...
"Smile."
Stop! Stop!
Stop.
Um...
Hi. I should have called.
I brought matzo ball soup. What?
What's the goddamn song called?
"Heaven Is A Car"!
Helpful. healing music!
- Wait.
- You just have to just produce something!
- Come on.
- Put your hands on the keyboard...
- Don't say nothing. The doctor's in there.
- ...and make some noise...
- of some kind! I don't care what...
- What's happening?!
at this point!
Come here. Here. you sit down. you sit.
It's too many. It's too many.
I take away because
it makes him more crazy.
Dr. Eugene give him too much.
He's more loco than Mr. Brian.
It's too many pills...
- and it makes him crazy.
- Write the song!
Okay. okay.
Gloria?!
Go. go. go!
Gloria!
Oh. Hey. Melinda.
- Hi. Gene.
- Wow. uh. what are you doing here?
You know. I brought Brian some soup.
Matzo ball.
Jesus Christ.
This is like a sodium bomb.
Brian cannot eat that. Sorry.
Is... is he okay?
He's great.
He's never been better. actually.
Gloria. can you make me a...
make me an Arnold Palmer?
Thanks.
So...
uh... listen. actually.
I'm very glad that you're here.
Um... we are finally
recording the new album...
and. um...
Brian is working on his autobiography.
So he's very busy...
and he will not be able
to see you anymore.
You can't do that. Gene.
Yes. I can.
Melinda. honest to God...
who are you really thinking about here?
Brian or yourself?
Thank you.
Well. I'd really like
to say goodbye to him.
Well. he's resting right now.
Well. I can wait.
My rules. Melinda.
and it's for his own good.
And yours. too. frankly.
Can you make me
an Arnold Palmer. please?
What the hell is wrong with you today?
Just make me a goddamn Arnold Palmer.
Sure.
No.
You have my sympathy.
Is this Audree Wilson?
You don't know me. but I am a friend...
of your son. Brian.
Well. I. um...
I'm sorry. this is awkward
calling you out of the blue...
but. um. well. I'm just concerned...
that he is not getting the best care.
Oh. well. I met him a few months ago.
He came... I'm... I sell Cadillacs.
Carl. hi.
My name is Melinda Ledbetter...
and Dr. Landy is...
I... I understand that there
are some legal complications...
so I... well...
you know I just...
I wanted you to... to...
A choke of grief...
Heart hardened. I...
Beyond belief...
A broken man too tough to cry...
Surf's up...
Aboard a tidal wave...
Come about hard...
and join the young...
and often spring you gave.
I heard the word...
Wonderful thing...
A children's song...
What do you say. Brian?
It's been over two hours.
I'm not sure.
It's just hostile in here right now.
The vibrations aren't right.
Okay. let's cancel the session.
Are you sure?
It's going to cost like $5.000.
with everybody here.
Let's cancel it.
I can't work.
I don't know. the vibrations
are just all wrong tonight.
Two. three. go.
That was it. That was the one.
Cut it. print it.
That's about as good a job
as it's going to get. right there.
Don't have to be that way.
It's not my fault.
All right. it's late.
I know. let's go then.
We're waiting around. waiting on you.
Brian. we've been waiting on you. man.
Brian!
Brian. come on.
Brian. I thought we were
going to have a serious meeting.
A band meeting.
Hey. you guys shouldn't talk over there.
Let's everybody come to the deep end.
We can't stand in the deep end. Brian.
We're too shallow for the deep end.
Listen. cousin. we're not...
we're not going to let you
do this to us anymore.
The lyrics on this album
do not make any sense.
"To ride in the rough
and sunny down snuff"?
What is that?
It's a gothic cowboy trip.
Brian. tell them.
The lyrics don't matter. all right?
It's about the music.
Throw the lyrics out.
They're just words.
We need to throw you out.
I'm telling you. Brian.
we need to destroy this shit...
- before it destroys us.
- Hey...
everybody please whisper.
Let's... let's come to the other side.
I have been writing lyrics professionally
since I was 14 years old.
- I don't need to be here.
- Good. then go! Please.
It's safer for everyone on the deep end!
We have got to finish this album
and we are not going to do it this way.
Not in these fragments!
Breaking it up and moving us all around.
The house is bugged.
Okay. Phil Spector has the house bugged.
He's a violent gangster
and he's angry at me.
Dad is listening in all the time!
Just whisper. okay?!
- I know what I'm talking about!
- We're not going to whisper. Brian!
Jeez.
Tell him it's over.
You and I are going
to rewrite these songs...
put them together in a normal album
and get on with it.
Just us!
Family first. right?
Okay. right. well...
Now. can we have a serious meeting now?
I want to do a chanting album.
Okay? No words. All Hawaiian singing.
And we can turn it
into a children's show for television.
And it'll be completely unstructured...
and it'll be about animals
and eating right.
Ma ha le lu lei...
Ma ha le lu lai...
Keene wakapulah...
Everyone.
Ma ha le lu lei...
Ma ha le lu lai...
I'm worried about you. brother.
I think I might be losing it.
I don't blame you.
There's a lot to lose out there.
It's a lot harder
than I thought it would be.
Yeah. it is.
We just got to stick together. brothers.
We just got to stick together.
It'll all be okay.
Where is everybody?
Did you fire them. too?
They're working on the new album.
They think they can simplify
what I was doing and release it.
So. uh. to satisfy the record company.
"Smiley smile."
Your masterpiece.
Cheer up. I got good news.
I sold the publishing rights
to A&M Records.
$750.000.
What?
I sold the rights
to the Beach Boys music.
Got the most I could for it.
not as much as I wanted...
but something.
They're...
our songs. You can't do that.
I did.
Anyway. what are you worried about it?
They're never going
to amount to anything.
You've peaked. Brian. Look around.
Five years from now
no one is going to remember you...
or the Beach Boys.
What was I supposed to do?
That's all I got. You fired me!
Your own father.
Now...
maybe we can be a family again.
So. in fact. you're saying...
that there should be a code of ethics...
that we abide by. Correct?
Absolutely. and that's what
the entire argument's about.
Dan Rather just wanted
to get to the bottom...
of the Iran-Contra situation...
What do you want?
I'm sorry to bother you.
but he wants to see you.
Now.
I have nothing to say to that man.
I'm not talking about Dr. Landy.
I'm talking about Brian.
Gene doesn't know I'm here.
Brian sent me.
He needs you. Melinda.
Can I take you to him?
- Hey.
I'm glad you came.
- It's been a while.
- Yeah.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- I'm sorry I couldn't come to see you.
It's been a...
Gene had to give me a day off. you know?
It's been real. real busy.
He wouldn't let me out.
Well...
It's really hard making a record.
- You know?
- You don't... you don't look well.
- Are you okay?
- Nuh-uh.
I feel awful.
I fall asleep everywhere I go.
I'm nauseous all the time.
Gene is really
a tough producer. you know?
I mean. I don't really. uh...
know what he wants.
He's really demanding.
And. uh...
I'm. uh... I'm...
I'm signing contracts
all the time and documents.
Making record deals and I don't know...
I don't know what's...
I don't know what's going on.
- You know what I mean?
- Brian. you need...
- you need real care.
- I miss you. I miss my family.
I miss you.
I want to be with you. You understand?
- I want to be with you.
- Okay.
- Okay?
But. I. um...
I hear voices.
- Since when?
- 1963.
- Are you kidding?
- No kidding.
I just didn't tell you
'cause I didn't want to scare you away.
I'm right here.
- I'm right here.
- I can't live this life anymore.
- Okay.
- It's a hellhole.
- Please.
- Then let's go.
I don't... how?
You and me...
we're going to walk
out of here right now.
And everything will change. Okay?
- Yeah. that's what I want.
- Great.
If you're ready. I'm ready.
- Yes. I want to be with you.
- I'm ready.
- Okay.
- Let's... let's go.
All right.
Hey. guys.
Wow. it really sounds
like I missed something here. Huh?
Hey. Brian?
- Brian.
- Listen to me. man.
- No.
- I'm really sorry that you feel like...
you live in a hellhole.
I had no idea.
You know. I've really tried
to make you feel comfortable. man.
Why can't I be with her. Gene?!
For the same reason. man.
that you cannot be with anybody.
You're sick.
Look at you. man. You're sick...
but you're going to get better.
Come into the control room. please.
- Let's walk out of here.
- Hey. what's it going to take. Melinda?
A court order?
You really want to push it that far?
I told you to stay away.
- Come on. let's go.
- If you stray from the program. you lose.
Everything will change.
We'll walk out of here.
- I can't be here.
- You can see your friends...
and your family
and you can get your life back.
- Brian. please.
- Do you understand?
- You asked me here.
- If I let you go...
- you're going to spiral down.
- Well. I'm here!
I came! You'll come with me.
I love you. I love you.
- And you're going to die here.
- I'll have to put you in an institution.
Brian. look at me.
Look at me. stay with me. Listen...
you need to get back to your life.
You need to get back to yourself.
Who you are inside.
Please. baby. please come with me.
There's no way out.
No way out.
You know I love Brian.
I love him very much...
but with everything
that he's gone through...
it feels a little selfish
wanting to be with him right now.
I do not want to be
one more person in his life...
who wants something from him.
So I'm going to walk away.
But I cannot leave him
in that house with Gene.
I can't.
I can't even think of him there.
Gene is killing Brian.
Gloria. I know you know.
You know better than anyone.
You're seeing it every day.
I need your help.
Dr. Eugene said
he's going to call immigration...
because he knows I have no papers...
- but I don't care.
- What he is doing to you...
to Brian. he is a monster.
We cannot let this go on.
I just need something.
Something to bring to Brian's family.
Something we can use against Gene.
Help me.
Brian! Come in here!
I think she just smiled!
Oh. man. Come... come see.
It's her first smile!
She's got your smile.
Oh. yeah.
Oh. yeah. this is it.
They find it in the printer.
It's very lucky. Very. very lucky.
- Sí.
- Oh.
Oh. this is it.
Carl Wilson. please.
Carl. hi.
It's Melinda Ledbetter.
I'm fine. Thanks.
Listen. I have
some important information...
that I need to share with you.
It's about your brother and Dr. Landy.
Yes. Yes.
It's that way.
Oh. really? Oh. wow.
Her own little office. huh?
Private office. Wow.
Our little girl is really moving up
in the world. huh?
Oh. for Christ's sake!
Don't tell me she's not here.
- Dr. Eugene Landy?
- Yes. what?
You've been served.
Oh. wow.
Oh. you bitch.
Um. do you think
that you've won. Melinda?
You know what?
I'm going to beat this
and I'm going to beat you!
Oh. my God.
You know. this kind of behavior
is so transparent.
It is so sick and manipulative!
Do you really think
that you are so different?
Oh. my God. You...
slut!
Slut!
And what is it?
What are you going to do?
You're going to make yourself believe
that you love him?
Is that it?
And that's going to make you
feel better about yourself. isn't it?
And it's going to assuage
your filthy little conscience...
while you are sucking him dry!
You are robbing him blind!
Well. get in line...
you little bitch!
Open the door! I know you're in there!
You all right?
I'm fine. Yeah. I'm fine.
So. what are you going to do now?
I'm going to go sell some cars.
- You disgust me.
- They call you a genius.
- Well. I'm a genius. too.
- Family first.
- You are nothing.
- You stole everything from me.
- You're amazing.
- I want you to see yourself dead.
- You're nothing.
- Listen to me.
I'm the way out.
- You need to get back to your family.
- I'm going to kill you.
- A winner never quits...
- You need to get back to yourself.
- Dad? Dad?
- ...and a quitter never wins.
- You need to get back to you.
- ...such a disappoint... Brian.
- Who you are.
- You disgust me.
- What's wrong with you?
- You need to get back to you.
There's a world where I can go...
and tell my secrets to.
In my room.
Brian.
Your dad...
In my room...
My room.
How many times
do I have to tell you this. Brian?
You don't do it all by yourself. Brian.
You need us as much as we need you.
Brian. I love you! Get up!
I won't desert you. Brian.
Don't worry.
Brian. I spoke to Carl.
He's going to get you out of here.
They say I can't see you anymore. Brian.
How long will the wind blow?
You need to find a way
to get back to yourself.
Until I die...
Till I die...
These things I'll be until I die.
Come find me. Brian.
until I die...
These things I'll be until I die.
These things I'll be...
until I die.
These things I'll be until I die.
These things I'll be...
Hi.
- Hi!
- How are you?
Well. gee. you just
scared me half to death.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry about that.
What are you doing here?
Looking for you.
Well. you look good.
You look really good. too.
Do you think it's a sign?
- What?
- You almost killing me?
I did not almost kill you.
You jumped in front of my car.
- What are you doing here?
- Oh. no. no.
Do you think we could
go out on a date again?
What?
Can we... me and you...
go out on a date?
Gene's gone. Look. I'm alone.
Really.
I got some state-appointed
someone or another...
managing all my things and...
Could you at least drive me home?
- Right now?
- Yeah. yeah.
Brian. I...
You know. I have an appointment.
I'm on my way somewhere.
I don't think I can get all the way...
- to Malibu right now.
- I don't live in Malibu anymore.
I'm off the beach for good.
- Really?
- Just... let me get in. Just five minutes.
I want to show you something. Okay?
- Let me show you something.
- Okay. getting in my car.
It won't take long.
- Okay. where are we going?
- Uh. take a right.
Turn here to get on.
Yeah. okay. that way.
So you live here now?
I didn't say I wanted you
to take me to where I live.
I said I wanted you to take me home.
This is where I grew up.
I wanted to show you.
All right. see that street?
119th Street?
- Yes.
- See that street? Do you see it?
Take a left here.
Uh-oh.
Welcome home.
You didn't know?
You hungry? You want something to eat?
You want. maybe. to go for a drive?
Or. maybe we could
find someplace to drive together?
And then what?
Wouldn't it be nice if we were older?...
Then we wouldn't have to wait so long...
And wouldn't it be nice
to live together...
In the kind of world where we belong?...
You know. it's gonna make it
that much better...
When we can say good night
and stay together...
Wouldn't it be nice
if we could wake up...
In the morning when the day is new?...
And after having spent
the day together...
Hold each other close
the whole night through...
Happy times together
we've been spending...
I wish that every kiss
was never ending...
Well. wouldn't it be nice?...
Maybe if we think and wish...
And hope and pray. it might come true...
Run. run. wee-ooh...
Baby. then there wouldn't be...
A single thing we couldn't do...
- We could be married
- We could be married...
And then we'd be happy...
I was sitting in a crummy movie...
With my hands on my chin...
Thank you.
Oh. the violence that occurs...
Seem like we never win...
Love and mercy.
that's what you need tonight...
So. love and mercy to you
and your friends tonight...
I was sittin' in my room.
and the news came on TV...
Na. na. na. na...
A lotta people out there hurting...
And it really scares me...
Na. na. na. na...
Love and mercy.
that's what you need tonight...
So. love and mercy to you
and your friends tonight...
I was standin' in a bar and watching
all the people there...
Na. na. na. na...
Oh. the loneliness in this world...
Well. it's just not fair...
Na. na. na. na...
Hey. love and mercy.
that's what you need tonight...
So. love and mercy to you
and your friends tonight...
Love and mercy tonight...
Good night. everybody. Drive safely.
Just driftwood floating on the sea...
Searching for the me...
And all that I have known to be...
Thank God that you noticed me...
And brought back harmony...
To this lonely soul...
Oh. it's a revelation...
I feel alive again...
There are no limitations with love...
The day you said that you'd be mine...
I can see Cloud Nine...
'Cause I was flying over it...
I wasted so much time...
Running in circles in my mind...
I couldn't hear my heart...
Calling out for you...
There's only one kind of love...
The kind that I've been dreaming of...
Don't you know it's unconditional?...
And when you hold love in your hand...
Only then you'll understand...
It's everything
that you've been wishing for...
Sometimes from out of the blue...
An angel comes to you...
But you've got to have an open heart...
I nearly failed the test of time...
But now that you are mine...
Girl. I'm here to stay...
Oh. it's a revelation...
I feel alive again...
There are no limitations with love...
There's only one kind of love...
The kind that I've been dreaming of...
Don't you know it's unconditional?...
And when you hold love in your hand...
Only then you'll understand...
It's everything
that you've been wishing for...
Da. da. da-da...
Doo-doo. doo-doo...
Da-da...
There's only one kind of love...
The kind that I've been dreaming of...
Don't you know it's unconditional?...
And when you hold love in your hand...
Only then you'll understand...
It's everything
that you've been wishing for...
Okay. it'll be at this tempo.
One. two...
one. two. three. four.
How far are we going. Brian?
Where we were originally.
as soon as... let's see...
- Gotta keep...
- New track. Take one.
- Count it. please.
- One. two. one. two. three.
All right. hold it for a second. please.
Just rest for one second.
I'll be right out.